A new day is dawning.
The Harder They Fall is a western film directed by Jeymes Samuel.
Gunning for revenge, outlaw Nat Love saddles up with his gang to take down enemy
Rufus Buck, a ruthless crime boss who just got sprung from prison.
Nat Love, played by Jonathan Majors.
Rufus Buck, played by Idris Elba.
Trudy Smith, played by Regina King.
Stagecoach Mary, played by Zazie Beetz.
Bass Reeves, played by Delroy Lindo.
Cuffee, played by Danielle Deadwyler.
The Harder They Fall is a 2021 American Western film directed by Jeymes Samuel (in his
feature directorial debut), who co-wrote the screenplay with Boaz Yakin.
The film stars Jonathan Majors, Idris Elba, Zazie Beetz, Regina King, Delroy Lindo,
Lakeith Stanfield, RJ Cyler, Danielle Deadwyler, Edi Gathegi, and Deon Cole.
It is one of few Westerns whose principal cast members are all Black.
Its characters are based on real cowboys, lawmen, and
outlaws of the nineteenth-century American West.
The Harder They Fall premiered at the BFI London
Film Festival on October 6, 2021.
It received a limited release on October 22, 2021, prior
to streaming on Netflix on November 3.
The film explores themes of prison, release from
prison, revenge, bank robbery, cowboy.